TeleLearning Network Inc. fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Administrative and operational subject files, 1994 - 2002; F-172-2; 76 cm of textual records 51.3 mb. of textual records (electronic)
  - Proposal review guidelines, 1999; F-172-2-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 172-10)
  - Strategic Plan, 1999-2002, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
  - Technology mediated learning report, 1998; F-172-2-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
  - TeleLearning correspondence (early years), 1994 - 1996; F-172-2-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
  - Theme 3 workshop on web technology:" Developing Collaborative Applications Using the World Wide Web 'Shell'", 1997; F-172-2-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
  - Virtual U training session, 1996; F-172-2-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
  - Beacon overviews, 1996; F-172-2-0-0-49
  - Bylaws - electronic file, 1996 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-50
  - Disclosures, 1999 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-51
  - Midterm review 1998, vol. 4, F-172-2-0-0-52
  - Network internal agreement - electronic file, 1995 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-53
  - Organization charts, 1996 - 2001; F-172-2-0-0-54
  - NCE renewal application, vol. 3, 1996 - 2002; F-172-2-0-0-55
  - Travel policy, 2001; F-172-2-0-0-56
  - Research budget, Phase II (1999/02), F-172-2-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 172-11)
- Financial files, 1995 - 2002; F-172-3; 25 cm of textual records 11.7 mb. of textual records (electronic)
  Series consists of records relating to the management of TeleLearning's finances. Activities documented include budget planning, preparation of year-end documentation, tax and information returns, funding applications, distribution of funds, and audits. Records include budgets, spreadsheets, financial statements and supporting papers, tax and information returns, applications, correspondence and reports. Both paper and electronic records have been retained, and there is some duplication of documents across media. Electronic records are retained in their original software formats (.doc, .xls).
  Other information relating to Network finances can also be found in some files in series F-172-2, "Administrative and operational subject files." High-level financial summaries are included among the meeting supporting papers in sub-series F-172-1-1, "Board of Directors meeting records."
  - Additional funding to researchers, 2002; F-172-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Audit information, 1999 - 2000; F-172-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - BDO Dunwoody - audit, 2001 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
    BDO Dunwoody; Textual records
  - Budget planning - administration, vol. 1, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - administration, vol. 2, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - administration, vol. 3, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - administration, vol. 4, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - projects, vol. 1, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - projects, vol. 2, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 172-12)
  - Budget planning - projects, vol. 3, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Budget planning - projects, vol. 4, 1996 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Extension funding application, 2001; F-172-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Extension funding - financial portion, 2001 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Extension Funding - financial portion, 2001 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Financial admin guidelines, 1996; F-172-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Tax returns and information returns, 2002; F-172-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/96, 1996; F-172-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/97, 1997; F-172-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/98, 1998; F-172-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/99, 1999; F-172-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/00, 2000; F-172-3-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/01, 2001; F-172-3-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Year end documents - Mar 31/02, 2002; F-172-3-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Period end documents - Sep 30/02, 2002; F-172-3-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 172-13)
  - Administrative funding, 1997 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-25
  - Audit, 1999 - 2001; F-172-3-0-0-26
  - Budgets, 1995 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-27
  - Infrastructure awards, 1997 - 2001; F-172-3-0-0-28
  - Membership, 1995 - 2001; F-172-3-0-0-29
  - Research funding, 1995 - 2002; F-172-3-0-0-30
- Communications files, 1994 - 2002; F-172-4; 46 cm of textual records 1629.4 mb. of multiple media records (electronic) 43 items photographic material 5 optical disks 4 artifacts; Physical description: 9 photographs located in F-172-4-1-0-2 Physical description: 7 photographs located in F-172-4-6-0-4 General note: photographic material is located in sub-series 1 and 6.
  This series consists of records relating to the communications function. Activities documented include development of a communications plan, media relations, advertising and publicity, production of the Network electronic newsletter "Tele-Chat," maintenance of the TeleLearning web site, and delivery of papers, presentations and reports concerning the Network. Records include correspondence, reports, press releases, press clippings, web site, artwork, logos, graphics, photographs and negatives, papers and presentations, and TeleLearning demonstration products on compact disk. Records are retained in both paper and electronic media.
  File and item lists are
  - Communications Manager's subject files, 1995 - 2000; F-172-4-1; 31 cm of textual records 9 photographs; General note: photographs are located in file F-172-4-1-0-2.
    Sub-series consists of the working files created by the Communications Manager. Activities documented include media and public relations, government relations, development of a communications plan and strategy, committee work (the Networks of Centres of Excellence Communications Committee and the TeleLearning Operations Committee), web site development, and projects (the "Collaborations" CD ROM and a joint TeleLearning and Office of Learning Technology Writing Project).
    Records include correspondence, reports, notes and working papers, communication plans, meeting agendas and minutes, proposals, work plans, agreements and contracts (copies), invoices, budget papers, purchase orders, estimates, permission forms, surveys, evaluation forms, contact lists, media releases, interview notes, presentations, advertising copy, newsletters and reprints. Photographs are included in file 2, "Annual report in progress." Records are retained in paper medium only.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by file title.
    - Advertising and public relations, 1998; F-172-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Annual report in progress, 1998 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
      Contains photographs.
      Textual records; Photographic materials
    - Collaborations CD ROM project, vol. 1, 1998 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Collaborations CD ROM project, vol. 2, 1998 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Collaborations CD ROM project, vol. 3, 1998 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Collaborations CD ROM project, vol. 4, 1998 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Collaborations CD ROM project - permission forms, 1998; F-172-4-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Communications Plan, 1996 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 172-14)
    - Conference - Montreal 1999, 1996 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Correspondence, 1999 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Government relations, 1999; F-172-4-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Media - issues management, 1995 - 1997; F-172-4-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Media correspondence, 1997 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Media lists, 1996 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Media relations - correspondence, 1996 - 1998; F-172-4-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Media releases / coverage, 1997 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Meetings, 1997 - 2000; F-172-4-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - NCE Communications Committee, 1997 - 1998; F-172-4-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - NCE program, 1995 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 172-15)
    - Office of Learning Technology / TeleLearning Writing Project, 1998 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Operations Committee, 1999; F-172-4-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Researcher information, 1997 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Strategy, 1996; F-172-4-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Translations, 1996 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Web site, 1995 - 1999; F-172-4-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
  - Media releases and clippings, 1994 - 2002; F-172-4-2; 6 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of media releases created by TeleLearning, as well as articles, transcripts and other material relating to TeleLearning collected by the Network to monitor its media coverage. Records are retained in paper medium only.
    - Press clippings, 1994 - 1997; F-172-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Press clippings, 1998; F-172-4-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Press clippings, 1999; F-172-4-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Press clippings, 2000 - 2002; F-172-4-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Press clippings - controversies, 1996 - 1997; F-172-4-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
    - Press releases, 1995 - 2001; F-172-4-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 172-16)
  - TeleLearning web site, 2002; F-172-4-3; 284.4 MB of mutliple media records (electronic); Physical description: sub-series consists of 1 optical disc.
    Sub-series consists of the TeleLearning web site as it was in September 2002, when it was burned onto a compact disk. Earlier versions of the web site were not preserved. The main sections include Home page, Profile, Activities and events, Research projects, Conference, Contact, K-12, Post-secondary, Teachers, Workplace, En français, Talk to us, and a Member / researcher section.
    For records relating to the development and maintenance of the web site, see sub-series F-172-4-1 "Communications Manager's subject files," file 25 "Web site."
    A printout of the basic directory structure is available with the CD ROM.
    - TeleLearning website, September 18, 2002; F-172-4-3-0-0-1 (Optical disc: cd OBJ-1059)
      Multi-media
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item11.
  - TeleLearning demonstration disks, 1997 - 2001; F-172-4-4; 1241.6 MB of multiple media records (electronic); Physical description: sub-series includes 4 optical discs.
    Sub-series consists of compact disks (CDs) containing TeleLearning products for public demonstration. Demonstrations include an internet course reader, course delivery and course enhancement software for the internet, and a practitioner's guide to telelearning.
    Items are arranged alphabetically.
    An item list is available.
    - Collaborations: A Practitioner's Guide to TeleLearning, September 30, 1998; F-172-4-4-0-0-2 (Optical disc: cd OBJ-1057, Optical disc: cd OBJ-1058)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item14, F-172-item15.
    - The Internet Course Reader: Demo, 2001; F-172-4-4-0-0-3 (Optical disc: cd OBJ-1060)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item12.
    - Virtual-U: course delivery and course enhancement software for the World Wide Web, 1997; F-172-4-4-0-0-1 (Optical disc: cd OBJ-1061)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item13.
  - Tele-Chat electronic newsletter, 1998 - 2002; F-172-4-5; 2.7 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    This sub-series consists of the electronic documents that comprised the newsletter. Records are retained in their original software formats (.doc).
    Files are arranged chronologically by issue.
    - Tele-Chat '98, 1998; F-172-4-5-0-1
    - Tele-Chat '99, 1999; F-172-4-5-0-2
    - Tele-Chat '01, 2001; F-172-4-5-0-3
    - Tele-Chat '02, 2002; F-172-4-5-0-4
  - Photographs, graphics and artifacts, 1996 - 2002; F-172-4-6; 100.7 mb. of mulitple media records (electronic) and other material; Physical description: sub-series includes 135 negatives, 16 contact sheets, 73 digital photographs (.jpg, .gif, .pct formats), 26 photographic transparencies, 7 photographic prints, 5 slides, 3 plaques, 1 sculpture, and 1 scrapbook.
    Sub-series consists of visual material and artifacts relating to TeleLearning events, officers (portraits), promotional material and awards. Records include photographs, graphics, artwork, flyers, logos, sample letterhead, a photo scrapbook, and awards (Gallery of Superb Printing in BC and a Public Sector Partnership Award). Media include paper, prints, negatives, contact sheets, artifacts (placques and a sculpture), and electronic records in their original software formats (.jpg, .eps, .tif, .pct, and .gif).
    Other files containing photographs are found in series F-172-4-1 "Communications Manager's subject files" file 2 "Annual report in progress."
    File and item lists are available.
    - Award: Gallery of Superb Printing in BC Certificate of Merit 1996-1997, F-172-4-6-0-0-2
      Graphic materials
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item1.
    - Award: Gallery of Superb Printing in BC Certificate of Merit 1996, F-172-4-6-0-0-1
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item2.
    - Award: Gallery of Superb Printing in BC Certificate of Merit 1997, F-172-4-6-0-0-3
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item3.
    - Award: Partnership Award (Public Sector) TeleLearning 2000, F-172-4-6-0-0-4; Glass
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item4.
    - Photo scrapbook, [199-?]; F-172-4-6-0-0-6
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item6.
    - Contact sheets, [199-?]; F-172-4-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
      Includes 16 contact sheets.
    - Graphics, [199-?]; F-172-4-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
      Textual records; Graphic materials
    - Negatives and transparencies, [199-?]; F-172-4-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
      Includes 26 photographic transparencies and 135 negatives.
    - Photographs and slides, F-172-4-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
      Includes 7 photographic prints and 5 slides.
    - Publications, promotions, letterhead, 1996 - 2000; F-172-4-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 172-5)
    - Artwork and Logos, 1996 - 2002; F-172-4-6-0-6
      Textual records; Graphic materials; Records in electronic form (born-digital)
    - Flyers, 1999 - 2001; F-172-4-6-0-7
      Textual records; Records in electronic form (born-digital)
    - Photos, 1997 - 2002; F-172-4-6-0-8
      Includes 73 digital photographs.
      Textual records; Photographic materials; Records in electronic form (born-digital)
  - Papers, presentations and reports, 1997 - 2002; F-172-4-7; 1 cm of textual records 43.9 mb. of textual records (electronic)
    Sub-series consists of reports about TeleLearning delivered by Network members in various venues, as well as reports commissioned by TeleLearning to summarize its activities and results. Records are retained predominantly in electronic media, maintained in their original software formats (.doc, .txt and .pdf); also included is a paper oversized book (originally bound) diagramming the "genealogy of research projects" conducted by the Network.
    - Genealogy of Research Projects at the TeleLearning Network of Centres of Excellence, 2000; F-172-4-7-0-0-1; Physical description: originally bound in scrapbook format.
    - Papers, 1997 - 2001; F-172-4-7-0-1
    - Presentations, 1999 - 2002; F-172-4-7-0-2
    - Research reports series, 1998 - 2000; F-172-4-7-0-3
  - Publications, 1996-2000; F-172-4-8; 6 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of publications produced by Telelearning Network of Centres of Excellence, including annual reports, preliminary and final conference programs, newsletters, and promotional booklets.
    - Publications, 1996-1997; F-172-4-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-31)
    - Publications, 1997-1998; F-172-4-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-31)
    - Publications, 1998-2000; F-172-4-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-31)
- TeleLearning Conference records, 1996 - 2001; F-172-5; 52 cm of textual records 92 sound recordings 40 artifacts; Physical description: includes 116 audio cassettes.
  This series consists of records relating to TeleLearning conferences. Activities documented include conference planning and organization, media relations, delivery of conference sessions, and post-conference evaluations.
  Records include conference material (programs, abtracts, and audio recordings of sessions); publicity material (brochures, posters, graphics and promotional artifacts); administrative records (correspondence, work plans, contracts and agreements, release forms, budgets, speakers and registration lists, media releases); and post-conference reports (debriefings, wrap-up reports, conference statistics).
  Series was arranged by the archivist into sub-series for each year's conference.
  See also series F-172-4 "Communications file" for additional information relating to TeleLearning conferences.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release and, as a result of the review, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  Access to the sound recordings is restricted for preservation reasons due to the fragility of the storage medium (audio cassette tape). The Archives will provide access only through digitizaiton of the originals. As of October 2012 no recordings have been digitized. Consult the reference archivist for more information about access these recordings.
  - Conference files: general, 1997 - 2001; F-172-5-1; 3 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of files relating generally to the TeleLearning annual conferences. Includes a file relating to the history of the conferences and speaker release forms relating to the audio recordings.
    Files are arranged chronologically.
    - Conferences - history, 1997 - 2000; F-172-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-1.
    - Audio taping authorization forms, 2000; F-172-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-2.
    - Audio taping authorization forms, 2001; F-172-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-3.
  - 1996 Montreal Conference files, F-172-5-2; 2 cm of textual records 1 sound recording; Physical description: includes 2 audio cassettes.
    Sub-series consists of material relating to the 1996 TeleLearning Conference held in Montreal.
    - TeleLearning 1996, 3 December 1996 - 7 December 1996; F-172-5-2-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3644, Audio cassette OBJ-3645)
      Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item16.
    - TeleLearning Conference - Montreal 1996, vol. 1, F-172-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-4.
    - TeleLearning Conference - Montreal 1996, vol. 2, F-172-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-5.
  - 1997 Toronto Conference files, F-172-5-3; 10 cm of textual records 7 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 8 audio cassettes.
    Sub-series consists of material relating to the 1997 TeleLearning Conference held in Toronto.
    - Opening plenary 1997, 5 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3646)
      Harasim, Linda; Marc Renaud; Bereiter, Carl; Calvert, Thomas W.; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item18.
    - Practice and Research In Workplace Training, 5 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3647)
      Carey, Tom; Gilbert Paquette; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item19.
    - K-12 State of the Art, 5 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3648, Audio cassette OBJ-3649)
      Marlene Scardamalia; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item20.
    - Evolution of Technologies and Evolution of Knowledge, 6 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3650)
      Papert, Seymour; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item22.
    - Theme 7 Integrative Question, 6 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3651)
      Thérèse Laferrière; John Willinsky; Jeff Taylor; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item23.
    - Post-Secondary State of the Art, 6 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3652)
      Calvert, Thomas W.; Harasim, Linda; Paul Bacsich; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item24.
    - TeleLearning banquet, 6 November 1997; F-172-5-3-0-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3653)
      Ronald Duhamel; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item25.
    - TeleLearning Conference - Toronto 1997, vol. 1, F-172-5-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-6.
    - TeleLearning Conference - Toronto 1997, vol. 2, F-172-5-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 172-17)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-5-0-0-7.
    - TeleLearning Conference - Toronto 1997: promotional material, F-172-5-3-0-3 (Urc tote box 172-29)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item7.
  - 1998 Vancouver Conference files, F-172-5-4; 2 cm of textual records 18 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 25 audio cassettes.
    Sub-series consists of material relating to the 1998 TeleLearning Conference held in Vancouver.
    - Human Computer Interaction (HCI) Workshop: Applying HCI methodology to usability studies of Telelearning applications, 14 November 1998; F-172-5-4-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3654, Audio cassette OBJ-3655, Audio cassette OBJ-3656)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item26.
    - Commercial Products and Platforms for Telelearning, 14 November 1998; F-172-5-4-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3657, Audio cassette OBJ-3658)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item29.
    - Machine Learning for Human Learning, 15 November 1998; F-172-5-4-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3659, Audio cassette OBJ-3660)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-172-item31.